<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quran on MeVsFalse</title>
    <link>https://mevsfalse.com/tags/quran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quran on MeVsFalse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevsfalse.com/tags/quran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does Allah have hands</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/hands.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/hands.html</guid>
      
      <description>Does Allah have hands? Qur&amp;rsquo;anic verses emphasizing that Allah is not like His creation and does not have a body. Also he is not a thing because all things are his creation and Allah is not created:
قُلۡ أَيُّ شَيۡءٍ أَكۡبَرُ شَهَٰدَةٗۖ قُلِ ٱللَّهُۖ شَهِيدُۢ بَيۡنِي وَبَيۡنَكُمۡۚ وَأُوحِيَ إِلَيَّ هَٰذَا ٱلۡقُرۡءَانُ لِأُنذِرَكُم بِهِۦ وَمَنۢ بَلَغَۚ أَئِنَّكُمۡ لَتَشۡهَدُونَ أَنَّ مَعَ ٱللَّهِ ءَالِهَةً أُخۡرَىٰۚ قُل لَّآ أَشۡهَدُۚ قُلۡ إِنَّمَا هُوَ إِلَٰهٞ وَٰحِدٞ وَإِنَّنِي بَرِيٓءٞ مِّمَّا تُشۡرِكُونَ 6:19 In Surah Al-An&amp;rsquo;am (6:19), the word shay’ (&amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo;) refers to Allah as the greatest witness.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abrogation of verses in Quran</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/abrogation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/abrogation.html</guid>
      
      <description>No Abrogation in the Qur’an
There is no abrogation (naskh) in the Qur’an. All its verses remain valid and harmonious. When chapter 2 mentions abrogation, it refers to the replacement of previous scriptures with the superior guidance of the Qur’an, not the cancellation of Qur’anic verses themselves.
۞مَا نَنسَخۡ مِنۡ ءَايَةٍ أَوۡ نُنسِهَا نَأۡتِ بِخَيۡرٖ مِّنۡهَآ أَوۡ مِثۡلِهَآۗ أَلَمۡ تَعۡلَمۡ أَنَّ ٱللَّهَ عَلَىٰ كُلِّ شَيۡءٖ قَدِيرٌ 2:106 Examples Often Misinterpreted as Abrogation .</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quran</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/tanzil.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/tanzil.html</guid>
      
      <description>1 بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
2 الْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ
3 الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
4 مَالِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ
5 إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
6 اهْدِنَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ
7 صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ الْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا الضَّالِّينَ
8 الم
9 ذَٰلِكَ الْكِتَابُ لَا رَيْبَ ۛ فِيهِ ۛ هُدًى لِّلْمُتَّقِينَ
10 الَّذِينَ يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْغَيْبِ وَيُقِيمُونَ الصَّلَاةَ وَمِمَّا رَزَقْنَاهُمْ يُنفِقُونَ
11 وَالَّذِينَ يُؤْمِنُونَ بِمَا أُنزِلَ إِلَيْكَ وَمَا أُنزِلَ مِن قَبْلِكَ وَبِالْآخِرَةِ هُمْ يُوقِنُونَ</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
