<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on MeVsFalse</title>
    <link>https://mevsfalse.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on MeVsFalse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mevsfalse.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abrogation of verses in Quran</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/abrogation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/abrogation.html</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction Abrogation (naskh) in the Qur&amp;rsquo;an refers to the concept that some verses were revealed with specific rulings that were later replaced or superseded by other verses. The idea is that earlier verses, while initially applicable, were later abrogated by new revelations that provided clearer or more comprehensive rulings.
Shah Waliullah Dehlavi, a prominent Islamic scholar and reformer from India, contributed extensively to Islamic thought and jurisprudence. He is known for his works on tafsir, fiqh (Islamic jurisprudence), and hadith, and he also made significant contributions to the understanding of abrogation (naskh) in the Qur&amp;rsquo;an.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of Esa</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/esa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/esa.html</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction Eesa is a Messenger of Allah and the second last Prophet for the Children of Israel. The ultimate and final Prophet for both the Children of Israel and all of humanity is Mohammad. In this divine lineage, Eesa&amp;rsquo;s mother is Mariam known as Hathor and Isis
His father is Zakariah and in ancient Egypt he is Osiris.
He is know as Horus in the Egyptian methology. He was aided by the Holy Spirit/ Amun Rouh or Ruh Alamin Yusuf.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of Yousuf</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/yusuf.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/yusuf.html</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction Yusuf, Yousuf or Joseph is one of the son of Jacob (Yaqoob). You can find him in the Egyptian methology with the name USeb (Geb).
Yusuf Name His name is Yusuf in the Quran. The alongation of U in his name leads us to his Egyptian name. In the story of Yusuf, he envisions himself as a bird on his head, and this is connected to his name, U Seb (Geb), which is why you might notice a quail chick on his head.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of Ismail</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/ismail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/ismail.html</guid>
      
      <description>Ismail Family Meet the prophet, Abraham, a.k.a Ibrahim or Ibraheem, the pioneer prophet in the Quranic saga. His father&amp;rsquo;s name is Azar. He has three children named Ismael, Ishaaq, and Yaqub. All three kids are considered prophets in the Quran.
Prophet Ismael goes by Ismail, Ishmael, and Ismaeil. He&amp;rsquo;s the first son of Ibrahim. The Quran talks about Ibrahim&amp;rsquo;s wife but doesn&amp;rsquo;t mention her name. Some traditions say it&amp;rsquo;s Sarah or Sara or Sarai, but that&amp;rsquo;s just a story and isn&amp;rsquo;t confirmed by the Quran.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musa is not Jibreel</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/musaisnotjibreel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/musaisnotjibreel.html</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction Anyone claiming that Moses is actually Gabriel and using Surat Sajdah, Ayah 23 to back it up is basically waving a flag that says, &amp;ldquo;I might need a Quranic compass.&amp;rdquo; Understanding the rich themes of the Quran is like diving into an epic adventure, and mixing up Moses and Gabriel? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s like confusing the message of quran.
32:23 وَلَقَدۡ ءَاتَيۡنَا مُوسَى ٱلۡكِتَٰبَ فَلَا تَكُن فِي مِرۡيَةٖ مِّن لِّقَآئِهِۦۖ وَجَعَلۡنَٰهُ هُدٗى لِّبَنِيٓ إِسۡرَـٰٓءِيلَ — Quran1</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darham (Money) in Quran</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/darham.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/darham.html</guid>
      
      <description>Quran sometimes throws in words from other languages. Let&amp;rsquo;s take words like Darham and more.
When yousuf was sold Allah&amp;rsquo;s playing 4D chess, going for &amp;ldquo;Darahim&amp;rdquo; in the Yousuf story instead of &amp;ldquo;Dinar.&amp;rdquo; Why? &amp;ldquo;Dinar&amp;rdquo; would be all about coins, but &amp;ldquo;Darahim,&amp;rdquo; straight from Sanskrit, brings that fixed trade value vibe. Allah, dropping knowledge ahead of the coin game that only kicked in during Justinian&amp;rsquo;s time around 541 CE. Peep the Turkish museum pic – that coin truth!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quran</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/tanzil.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/tanzil.html</guid>
      
      <description>1 بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
2 الْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ
3 الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
4 مَالِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ
5 إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
6 اهْدِنَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ
7 صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ الْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا الضَّالِّينَ
8 الم
9 ذَٰلِكَ الْكِتَابُ لَا رَيْبَ ۛ فِيهِ ۛ هُدًى لِّلْمُتَّقِينَ
10 الَّذِينَ يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْغَيْبِ وَيُقِيمُونَ الصَّلَاةَ وَمِمَّا رَزَقْنَاهُمْ يُنفِقُونَ
11 وَالَّذِينَ يُؤْمِنُونَ بِمَا أُنزِلَ إِلَيْكَ وَمَا أُنزِلَ مِن قَبْلِكَ وَبِالْآخِرَةِ هُمْ يُوقِنُونَ</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quran Translation</title>
      <link>https://mevsfalse.com/en_tanzil.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mevsfalse.com/en_tanzil.html</guid>
      
      <description>1 In the name of Allah, the Merciful, the Compassionate
2 Praise be to Allah, the Lord of the entire universe.
3 The Merciful, the Compassionate
4 The Master of the Day of Recompense.
5 You alone do we worship, and You alone do we turn for help
6 Direct us on to the Straight Way,
7 The way of those whom You have favoured, who did not incur Your wrath, who are not astray.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
